walkfree.org 2019-07-23

# Privacy Policy | The Minderoo Foundation

You can read the full details of our privacy policy below. As a quick summary:

If we ask for your personal information, we only ask for personal information that we need.

If you give us your personal information, we will treat it in accordance with our privacy policy.

This is the Privacy Policy of the Minderoo Foundation Pty Ltd as trustee for the Minderoo Foundation Trust (Minderoo). Our postal address is PO Box 3155, Broadway Nedlands, Western Australia, 6009.

###### Our commitment to privacy of personal information

We are committed to managing personal information in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and in accordance with other applicable privacy laws.

This document sets out our policy for managing personal information and is referred to as our Privacy Policy.

###### What we know about you from visiting our website

When you visit our website, our web server automatically records some general information about your visit. The information we record for statistical purposes is your server address, the date and time, the pages accessed and documents downloaded, the previous site visited, and the type of browser used. We may make these details available to third parties for the sole purpose of providing analysis of website traffic.

We use information from visitors to our website to improve the content of our website and analyse what pages people visit.

Cookies are only used on our website where required for website functionality. Disabling cookies should not affect your overall website experience. We do not collect or store personal or private information in any cookies originating from our website. However, Facebook and Google provide third party analytical services to us in respect of our website. A summary of information about how we use third party services and links is set out below. 

###### Google analytics and re-marketing

  * Google Analytics: a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage.
  * Google remarketing technology: a service which allows Google to display relevant content based on what pages on our website you have viewed. The content will be displayed using cookies. These cookies don’t record any personal information or identify you personally.

By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google for the purposes set out and in the manner described in Google’s data protection policy (which can be accessed here (https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)). You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or use the opt out service provide by Google here (https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

###### Facebook conversion tracking pixel

We may from time to time use Facebook Advertising, Facebook Pixel Re-Marketing, and communications. This tool allows us to understand and deliver content and make it more relevant to you. The collected data remains anonymous and we cannot see the personal data of any individual user.  
However, the collected data is saved and processed by Facebook. Facebook may be able to connect the data with your Facebook account and use the data for their own advertising purposes (in accordance with Facebook’s Data Use Policy found under: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). Facebook has ultimate control of the information gathered through Facebook Advertising, Facebook Pixel Re-Marketing, and communications. You can opt-out of Facebook’s use of cookies and Facebook Pixel Re-Marketing through settings on your Facebook Account.  

We also use interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and others. If you choose to “like” or “share” information from this website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your visits to this site with other personal information.

###### Links to third party websites

Our website may contain links to third-party websites. We are not responsible for the content of privacy practises of such third party websites.  
How and why does Minderoo collect and use your information

We collect personal information directly from you when you contact us, raise a general query or complaint with us, sign up to one of our mailing lists, or when we engage in our philanthropic activities with you. The purposes for which we usually collect and use personal information depends on the nature of your interaction with us, but may include: 

  * Responding to requests for information and other general enquiries
  * Informing you of activities and events with which we may have a connection
  * Responding to enquiries and complaints
  * When you apply for a career with us
  * Collecting and processing a donation you have made.

The types of personal information we may collect when you interact with us in the ways set out above include your name and contact details, and other information relevant to the nature of that particular interaction.

###### Research and partnerships

From time to time, we engage in research activities and collect data from individuals in an anonymised form.

We also collect and receive data from overseas providers or research institutions that undertake research projects on our behalf. Again, the data we receive from these organisations is generally in an anonymised form.  
On occasion we collect information about individuals through case studies or reports submitted to us from our partner organisations and from schools or universities who we provide scholarships. The types of personal information we receive in these circumstances includes name, address, date of birth, gender, photographs, academic records, employment records, income streams, family composition, health, disability information, culture and language.

We collect and record personal information about individuals such as contractors and subcontractors and potential contractors and subcontractors and their representatives in relation to those service providers supplying goods and services to us.

###### If you apply for a career with Minderoo

We collect personal information when recruiting personnel, such as your name, contact details, qualifications and work history. Generally, we will collect this information directly from you.

We may also collect personal information from third parties (eg referees you have nominated). Before offering you a position we may collect additional details such as your tax file number, superannuation information and other information necessary to conduct background checks to determine your suitability for certain positions (eg police clearances or working with children checks).

We do not know your email address unless you give it to us. We will only record your email address if you send us a message.

If you supply us with your email address or postal address, we might send you information on new projects or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know by sending us an email to hello@minderoo.com.au.

If you are participating or attending an event we are managing or delivering, we may take images or audio-visual recordings which identify you. We may use those images or audio-visual recordings which identify you for promotional purposes.  

You consent to us using your personal information for sending you information, including promotional material about us, as well as the products and services of our related entities and third parties, now and in the future. You also consent to us sending you such information by means of direct mail, telemarketing, email, SMS and MMS messages.

If you do not want to receive marketing information from us, you can unsubscribe in any of the following ways: by emailing us at hello@minderoo.com.au or by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in an automated mailout that you have received from us.  
Sensitive information

In limited circumstances we may collect information which is considered sensitive information, eg if you are injured at an event promoted or delivered by us we may collect health information about you in an emergency or otherwise with your consent.  
Can you deal with us anonymously

You may choose to remain anonymous or use a pseudonym in your communications with us where it is lawful and practicable. Sometimes we may require your real name, for example where you are applying for a career with us. 

If you choose not to provide your personal information to us for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, we may not be able to provide you with requested information, products or services, or to effectively conduct our relationship with you. 

###### How do we hold information

We aim to keep your personal information secure. We endeavour to take reasonable steps to protect your personal information from misuse, interference and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We also endeavour to take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify personal information that we no longer require.

We maintain physical security over paper and electronic data stores such as through locks and security systems at our premises. We also maintain computer and network security such as firewalls to protect your personal information and to control access to our computer systems. 

We secure communications between your browser and our websites with SSL/HTTPS encryption wherever possible. We encourage users of our website to exercise care in sending personal information via the internet. 

###### How do we use and disclose your information

We may use information that you provide to us internally and may share it with other people or organisations who need to know it as part of working with us in our normal business activities. For example we may disclose your personal information to:

  * Any of Minderoo’s internal divisions, business units or departments.
  * Other organisations or individuals who assist us in providing products and services to you on our behalf.
  * Representatives, agents or contractors who are appointed by us in the ordinary operation of our business to assist us in administering our business (such as for data storage or processing, printing, mailing, marketing, planning and product or service development).

###### Who has access to your information

We do not share your personal information with others except in accordance with this Privacy Policy or as permitted by the Privacy Act (including the Australian Privacy Principles) or other applicable privacy laws, and we do not sell your personal information to anyone for any purpose. 

Some of your personal information may be disclosed, transferred, stored, processed or used overseas by us, or by third party service providers. This may happen if our employees or contractors are located overseas, including in the United States of America and the United Kingdom. In these circumstances, you consent to the collection, use, storage and processing of your personal information in those countries, without us being responsible under the Privacy Act for such use (or for any breach). Where such parties are located overseas, you may have rights to enforce such parties’ compliance with applicable data protection laws, but you might not have recourse against those parties under the Australian Privacy Act in relation to how those parties treat your personal information. 

###### How can you access or seek correction of your personal information

If you would like to access personal information we may hold about you please email us at [hello@minderoo.com.au](mailto:hello@minderoo.com.au) to request it. You will not be charged for making a request to access your personal information but you may be charged for the reasonable time and expense incurred in compiling information in response to your request.

Please let us know if there are any errors or discrepancies in the personal information we hold about you or if your details have changed and we will take reasonable steps to correct and/or update this information.

We may decline your request to access or correct your personal information in certain circumstances in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles. If we do refuse your request, we will provide you with a reason for our decision and, in the case of a request for correction, we will include a statement with your personal information about the requested correction.

###### What should you do if you have a complaint about the handling of your personal information

Contact us at any time if you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or about the way in which your personal information has been handled or if you have a complaint about privacy by emailing us at hello@minderoo.com.au.

We will consider your questions, concerns or complaint to work out what steps can be taken to resolve this. If you make a complaint which requires detailed consideration or investigation, we may ask you to give us more information about your complaint and the outcome you are seeking. We may need to gather relevant facts, locate and review relevant documents and speak with other persons involved. If we cannot provide you with a response within one (1) week we will let you know.

###### How changes are made to this Privacy Policy

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, with or without notice to you. 

_This Privacy Policy was last updated on 18 February 2019._
